Guide to the Alliance of Queer Undergraduates at Duke (AQUADuke) records, 1973-1995
University Archives Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Alliance of Queer Undergraduates at Duke (AQUADuke) records 1973-1995
University Archives, Duke University
Duke University. Alliance of Queer Undergraduates at Duke.
1.5 Linear Feet 750 Items
The Alliance of Queer Undergraduates at Duke (AQUADuke) is committed to making Duke a more positive and affirming place for LGBTQ students by providing programming and events targeted at increasing awareness and creating comfortable, welcoming social space.
The materials in the collection include logbooks, flyers, agendas, newsletters, and financial records of the Gay Alliance and the Duke Gay and Lesbian Alliance. Subjects present include AIDS, legal issues, civil rights, and other matters. The dates of the material range from 1973-1995.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
Provenance
The Alliance of Queer Undergraduates at Duke (AQUADuke) records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1995.
Historical Note
A LGBT student organization has been present on the Duke Campus since the founding of the Duke Gay Alliance in 1972, however it has seen many name changes over the years. Past names include: Duke Gay and Lesbian Alliance; Duke Gay, Bisexual, and Lesbian Association (1994); and Gothic Queers (1997). In 2002, the organization took the name Alliance of Queer Undergraduates at Duke (AQUADuke).
AQUADuke is formally recognized by the Duke Student Government, and is Duke University's Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender and Questioning student organization. The group is non-exclusive and welcomes all those that are out and about, closeted and curious, or just open-minded. Their mission and purpose is to provide a safe and supportive environment for students questioning their sexuality while spreading awareness of LGBTQ issues, providing support for LGBTQ members of our community, and dealing with issues facing the LGBTQ community on and off the Duke University campus.
In Spring 2008, AquaDuke merged with Duke Allies to form Blue Devils United.
Collection Overview
The collection contains phone logbooks, flyers, agendas, newsletters, and financial records of the Gay Alliance, the Duke Gay and Lesbian Alliance, and the Duke Gay, Bisexual, and Lesbian Association. Subjects present include AIDS, legal issues, civil rights, local and national resources concerning gay issues, and other matters. The dates of the material range from 1973-1995.
The phone logbooks (1990-1992) are accounts of phone messages received by the organization, but they also acted as an information clearinghouse for the busy AQUADuke members serving as a central location to leave messages for other members providing insight into the organization's activities, concerns, and internal issues.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Bisexual college students -- North Carolina -- Durham.
Duke University -- Students -- Societies, etc.
Gay college students -- North Carolina -- Durham
Gay community -- North Carolina -- Durham.
Homosexuality and education -- United States.
Lesbian college students -- North Carolina -- Durham.
Transgender college students -- North Carolina -- Durham.
Related Material
Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgender Task Force records, 1991-1998.
University Archives. Duke University.
Rainbow Triangle Oral History Interviews, 1998-2003.
Duke University. David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library.
Contents of Collection
- Container List, 1 Box
  - Agendas and Flyers, 1988-1989, undated (Box 1)
  - AIDS Info, 1989-1990, undated
  - Bob Damron's Address Book, 1980 (gay men's travel guide)
  - Campus organizations: other schools, 1989, undated
  - Budget, financial documents, 1989-1990, undated (2 folders)
  - Duke LGB List electronic mail messages, 1995
  - Gay Alliance, 1973-1979(includes the Gay Morning Star the newsletter of the Duke Gay Alliance)
  - GLB Business, 1992-1993, undated, (includes promotional flyers)
  - Lambda Legal Defense, 1989-1990
  - Lesbian/Gay/Bisexual Resources at Duke
  - Lesbian/Gay/Bisexual Resources Local and State
  - Lesbian/Gay/Bisexual Resources National
  - Miscellaneous, flyers, clippings, newsletters, pamphlets (3 folders)
  - Newsletters and flyers, 1993, undated (periodicals include Q-Notes, Triangle Men of All Colors Together, The Front Page, V.O.I.C.E.S, The Newsletter)
  - Outlines, newsletter of the Duke Gay, Lesbian and Bisexual Association, vol. 1, no.1 (2 copies)
  - Pamphlets for reference
  - Phone Log Book, 1990
  - Phone log Book, 1990-1992
  - Pride 89, 1989
  - Religious Issues for Lesbians/Gays/Bisexuals
  - TALF (Triangle Area Lesbians)